[{
        "question": "Which method deletes a file in Java?",
        "options": [
            "file.delete()",
            "file.remove()",
            "file.garbage()",
            "file.dump()"
        ],
        "answer": "file.delete()",
        "explanation": "The file.delete() method is used to delete a file in Java."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which method in java is used to read lines from file?",
        "options": [
            "file.read()",
            "file.nextLine()",
            "file.getLine()",
            "All of these"
        ],
        "answer": "file.getLine()",
        "explanation": "The file.getLine() method is used to read lines from a file."
    },
    {
        "question": "The correct syntax to import the math library in java is ___.",
        "options": [
            "import java.lang.math",
            "import math",
            "import java.math",
            "All of these"
        ],
        "answer": "import java.lang.math",
        "explanation": "The correct syntax to import the math library in java is: import java.lang.math"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is/are valid method(s) of math library in java?",
        "options": [
            "max()",
            "cbrt()",
            "log10()",
            "All of these"
        ],
        "answer": "All of these",
        "explanation": "Some common methods of the math library are max(), min(), cbrt(), pow(), log(), log10(), etc."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which method in java is used to generate random numbers in Java?",
        "options": [
            "random.nextInt()",
            "random()",
            "rand()",
            "All of these"
        ],
        "answer": "random.nextInt()",
        "explanation": "The Java method random.nextInt() is used to generate random numbers."
    },
    {
        "question": "In java, recursion is ___.",
        "options": [
            "Method",
            "A process allowing methods to call itself",
            "The process to call methods",
            "None of these"
        ],
        "answer": "A process allowing methods to call itself",
        "explanation": "The recursion is a process by which a process allow methods to call itself."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is stringBuffer in java?",
        "options": [
            "Class to create a string array",
            "Class to create a mutable string in java",
            "Class to create a string from i/o buffer",
            "All of these"
        ],
        "answer": "Class to create a mutable string in java",
        "explanation": "StringBuffer class is used to create modifiable strings in java."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is a valid data structure in java?",
        "options": [
            "Array",
            "List",
            "Vector",
            "All of these"
        ],
        "answer": "All of these",
        "explanation": "All of the above (Array, List, and Vector) are valid data structures in Java."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which syntax is valid to create a vector in java?",
        "options": [
            "Vector < string > names = new Vector < String > ();",
            "Vector name = new string;",
            "int name = new vector ()",
            "All of these"
        ],
        "answer": "Vector < string > names = new Vector < String > ();",
        "explanation": "The syntax to create a vector in Java is: Vector < string > names = new Vector < String > ();"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will be the output of following Java code?\n\npublic class Main {\n  public static void main(String[] args) {\n    StringBuffer sb = new StringBuffer(\"include\");\n    sb.append(\"help\");\n    System.out.println(sb);\n  }\n}",
        "options": [
            "Error",
            "include",
            "help",
            "Includehelp"
        ],
        "answer": "Includehelp",
        "explanation": "The string here is a StringBuffer hence the contents can be edited which makes the append method work on it by adding 'help' to the end of the string."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a deadlock in Java?",
        "options": [
            "State when all processes have complete working and are dead",
            "State when threads are in hold state forever",
            "State when threads are not ready",
            "All of these"
        ],
        "answer": "State when threads are in hold state forever",
        "explanation": "Deadlock in Java is a condition when two or more threads try to access the same resources at the same time."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which graph is used to check for deadlock in Java?",
        "options": [
            "Deadlock graph",
            "Time graph",
            "Wait-for-graph",
            "None of these"
        ],
        "answer": "Wait-for-graph",
        "explanation": "The wait-for-graph is used to check for deadlock in Java."
    },
    {
        "question": "Batch processing in java is ___.",
        "options": [
            "Used to execute a group of queries or a batch as executing a single query, again and again, is time taking and reduce the performance",
            "Used to processing multiple queries can be executed at once",
            "Used to increase program's performance",
            "All of these"
        ],
        "answer": "All of these",
        "explanation": "Read more: Batch Processing in Java."
    },
    {
        "question": "Discuss the following Question",
        "options": [],
        "answer": "",
        "explanation": "convert the provided in the above provided solution in json format"
    }
]